<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-08T01:28:05+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ARENA</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Fiebach Lab</name></author><entry><title type="html">Go Woman</title><link href="/go-woman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Go Woman" /><published>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/go-woman</id><content type="html" xml:base="/go-woman/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goethe-university-frankfurt.de/127213570/GoWomen___Network_for_female__R3_scientists_and_newly_appointed_professors?locale=en">Network for female* R3 scientists and newly appointed professors</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Fiebach Lab</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Network for female* R3 scientists and newly appointed professors]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Equal Opportunities and Gender Equality Measures</title><link href="/equal-opp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Equal Opportunities and Gender Equality Measures" /><published>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/equal-opp</id><content type="html" xml:base="/equal-opp/"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.dfg.de/en/principles-dfg-funding/basics-and-principles-of-funding/equal-opportunities/applicants-funding-recipients/standard-allowance/career-development-measures">Career Development Measures for Female Researchers</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.dfg.de/en/principles-dfg-funding/basics-and-principles-of-funding/equal-opportunities/applicants-funding-recipients/standard-allowance/measures-to-promote-diversity">Measures to Promote Diversity</a></li>
      <li><a href="https://www.uni-frankfurt.de/95631092/Career_Support#a_566f31c6-af899f14">Measures for Equal Opportunities within the Research Alliance Equal Opportunities Office, Goethe University Frankfurt, 2024</a></li>
      <li><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06697-3">How female scientists can confront gender bias in the workplace</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Fiebach Lab</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Career Development Measures for Female Researchers Measures to Promote Diversity Measures for Equal Opportunities within the Research Alliance Equal Opportunities Office, Goethe University Frankfurt, 2024 How female scientists can confront gender bias in the workplace]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Events and Training Opportunities</title><link href="/events/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Events and Training Opportunities" /><published>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/events</id><content type="html" xml:base="/events/"><![CDATA[<h6 style="text-align: center;font-weight: bold;"> A European perspective on structural barriers to women`s career progression in neuroscience </h6>
<p><b>Date and Time:</b> 07th May 2024, 12:00 - 14:00 <br />
<b> Location: </b> Seminar room 5G 170,PEG, Westend Campus, Goethe University <br />
Despite an unprecedented number of women entering neuroscience, and decades-long recruitment and retention efforts, women continue to be disproportionately underrepresented in European academic tenure-track faculty and leadership positions. This Perspective focuses on two major career points where women exhibit diminished representation: the transition from postdoctoral fellow to junior professor and the promotion to more senior (tenured) faculty positions. We discuss below recently implemented country-specific and Europe-wide initiatives supporting equal career progression and propose further concrete steps to be taken to break down the structural barriers that prevent women’s progression up the academic career ladder as European neuroscientists. <br /></p>
<h6 style="text-align: center;font-weight: bold;"> Training for female scientists </h6>
<p>The Career Support – Training for Female Scientists* program offered by the Office for Equal Opportunities at Goethe University, offers variety of courses tailored to the specific needs of postdocs (R2 and R3). These training courses are measures designed to counteract the structural disadvantages faced by women* in the scientific field. For more information about the training module and events please visit: <a href="https://www.uni-frankfurt.de/95631092/Career_Support#a_566f31c6-af899f14">https://www.uni-frankfurt.de/95631092/Career_Support#a_566f31c6-af899f14</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Fiebach Lab</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A European perspective on structural barriers to women`s career progression in neuroscience Date and Time: 07th May 2024, 12:00 - 14:00 Location: Seminar room 5G 170,PEG, Westend Campus, Goethe University Despite an unprecedented number of women entering neuroscience, and decades-long recruitment and retention efforts, women continue to be disproportionately underrepresented in European academic tenure-track faculty and leadership positions. This Perspective focuses on two major career points where women exhibit diminished representation: the transition from postdoctoral fellow to junior professor and the promotion to more senior (tenured) faculty positions. We discuss below recently implemented country-specific and Europe-wide initiatives supporting equal career progression and propose further concrete steps to be taken to break down the structural barriers that prevent women’s progression up the academic career ladder as European neuroscientists. Training for female scientists The Career Support – Training for Female Scientists* program offered by the Office for Equal Opportunities at Goethe University, offers variety of courses tailored to the specific needs of postdocs (R2 and R3). These training courses are measures designed to counteract the structural disadvantages faced by women* in the scientific field. For more information about the training module and events please visit: https://www.uni-frankfurt.de/95631092/Career_Support#a_566f31c6-af899f14]]></summary></entry></feed>